Rushabh Wadkar

Full Stack Software Engineer

A dedicated and organized team player who loves taking a challenging and high-performance oriented role which contributes towards the growth of the organization. I am having 5 years of experience in product development, testing and deployment.



rushabh6792@gmail.com

9004196353

Mumbai, India

linkedin.com/in/rushabh-wadkar

github.com/rushabh-wadkar

stackoverflow.com/users/4008454

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Flextrade Systems (Domain: Finance)

01/2020 - Present

Pune FlexTrade Systems is a global leader in high performance multi-asset EMS and OMS for equities, fixed income, foreign exchange, futures, and options.

Responsibilities

- Worked on an Internal project from scratch based on React as frontend and python as backend (Golang used for some tooling)
- Awarded best project for the year 2020 and received appreciation from CEO, VP and client services team.
- Implementation of ssh based scripts & code execution on different servers much like AWS. Showing 50M logs on UI, optimizing html rendering, lazy loading and implemented various optimization techniques.
- Implemented monitoring system for CPU, Mem and Disk usage on deployed servers. Helped client services team to counter high disk usage and mem usage easily.
- Implemented and Integrated various flextrade company products. This enabled client services team to login at one place and view all at just a click.
- Implemented live backend logs fetching using golang and filebeat.
- Migrated to docker based deployment which reduced the deployment to a much greater extent.

Software Engineer

Vistaar Technologies (Domain: Medical Pharma)

07/2017 - 01/2020 Mumhai

Vistaar based in UnitedStates offers pricing software solutions and services across a range of industries

Responsibilities

- 2.4 years of experience in the areas of product development and testing with role responsibility right from analysis, coding, testing to deployment.
- Worked as individual contributor for developing software screens using ExtJS for front end and Rhino Engine JS for the backend logic.
- Monitoring setup logs, Uptime/Downtime of Production servers on Kibana. Building Automation Scripts in Linux for various operations.
- Server Maintenance(Setup Creation/Backup/Maintain). Also, Drop and Artifacts Deployment on the Production server. Database Management (Import/Export Dumps).

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science Bharti Vidyapeeth College Of Engineering

06/2013 - 06/2017

8 9 CPGA

Higher Secondary Certificate J.H.Ambani School (CBSE)

06/2011 - 06/2013 85.2%

SKILLS

Git & Mercurial Postman

ACHIEVEMENTS

Secured All India Rank 13 in NPTEL IIT MADRAS CERTIFICATION Online Certification - Data Science for Engineers

Score 84% - AIR-13 Topper 2% (http://bit.ly/2nptel7g)

Secured First Runner up position at Mumbai Hackathon 2017

Organized by Frappé Technologies

Secured First position in Data-Analysis competition (Winner)

Organized by Acrotrend Systems.

Awarded scholarship by Ratan Tata Trust for academic performance in First Year of Engineering, 2014.

Secured 2nd rank in the entire college.

CERTIFICATES

Java 1.7 (J2SE and J2EE) from NIIT Institute Excellent Grade (2015)

Big Data and Hadoop from TechData Institute, Vidyavihar.

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

Marathi

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Trekking **Badminton** **Table Tennis**